Finding Aid for Office of Student Community Relations (University of Michigan) records, 1961-1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Office of Student Community Relations (University of Michigan) records 1961-1971
University of Michigan. Office of Student Community Relations.
4 linear feet
87289 Bimu B7 2
Records, 1961-1971, of the Office of Student Community Relations of the University of Michigan, organization within the Office of Student Affairs; contain files largely relating to university regulations respecting student use of automobiles and bicycles, student housing, and other student concerns. Also contains earlier material inherited from other university offices.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Records were received from the Office of Student Community Relations (donor no. 5013 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
Shortly after assuming the Vice Presidency of Student Affairs on December 1, 1964, Richard Cutler created the Office of Student-Community Relations, while eliminating the offices of the Dean of Women and Dean of Men. The Office of Student-Community Relations was created to administer off-campus housing, student vehicle registration, and student-community concerns.
Under the subsequent Vice Presidency of Robert Knauss, who was elected to that position in 1970, the functions of the Student-Community Relations Office were absorbed by the Housing Division, creating a single unified housing structure as recommended in 1965 by The President's Commission on Off-Campus Housing.
The records include regulations regarding student automobiles and resulting parking and traffic problems (1922-1968), planning and regulation of bicycles and motorcycles, housing inspection, and other matters of student concern. The minutes of the University Council, composed of faculty members and students, containing emergency guidelines developed in 1970/1971 for dealing with campus unrest are included, as are a student credit union survey (1969), a health service study (1968-1969), and studies of university bookstores and campus recreation.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Student housing.; University of Michigan. Office of Student Affairs.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan. Office of Student Community Relations.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
University of Michigan--Campus--1959-1960.; Bicycles and tricycles.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Records
  - University Regulations and Planning Regarding Automobiles
    - Ban on Student Driving, 1922-1959
      - Publicity (Box 1)
      - Correspondence (Box 1)
      - Surveys (Box 1)
    - Driving Rules Revisions, 1961-1968
      - Driving Regulations Board, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
      - Legality of Regulations and Fees (Box 1)
      - Auto Study Commission, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
      - Student Traffic Advisory Board (Box 1)
      - Student Vehicle Bureau, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
      - Parking System Capabilities, 1968 (Box 2)
  - University Regulations and Planning Regarding. Motorcycles
    - Noise (Box 2)
    - Parking (Box 2)
    - Safety (Box 2)
  - University Regulations and Planning Regarding Bicycles (Box 2)
  - Housing
    - Student Advisory Committee on Housing
      - General (Box 2)
      - Subcommittee on Off-Campus Housing (Box 2)
    - Men's Housing Inspections, 1926-1946, 3 volumes (Box 3)
  - President's Commission on Role of Students in Decision Making (Box 3)
  - Legal Services for Student Use (Box 3)
  - University Council, 1968-1971
    - Campus Unrest (Box 4)
    - Emergency Guidelines (Box 4)
    - Rules and Procedures of University schools and colleges (Box 4)
  - Student Credit Union Survey, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Campus Recreation (Box 4)
  - Health Service Study Commission, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Student Bookstore (Box 4)
  - Photographs of Bicycle Parking Problems, 1959-1960 (Box 4)